Finding aid to the William L. MacDonald papers CA.MS.01137
Smith College Archives
William L. MacDonald papers
1965-2010
Smith College Archives
MacDonald, William L.
CA.MS.01137
0.229 linear feet (1 container)
William L. MacDonald became a member of the Smith College faculty in 1965, where he remained until his retirement in 1981. At Smith, MacDonald lectured on Classical Architecture. He became head of the department in 1974. His papers contain news clippings and photographs documenting his professional life as Professor of Art at Smith.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Biographical / Historical
William L. MacDonald was born in 1921. He served in the US Army Air Force from 1942 to 1945. MacDonald received his A.B. in 1949 and his A.M. in 1953, both from Harvard. He lectured at the Boston Architectural Center (1949-1953) and Wheaton College (1953-1954). In 1954, MacDonald was awarded a fellowship at the American Academy in Rome, which he held until 1956. In 1956, he completed his Ph.D. at Harvard and joined the Department of Art History at Yale. MacDonald became a member of the Smith College faculty in 1965, where he remained until his retirement in 1981. At Smith, MacDonald lectured on Classical Architecture. He became head of the department in 1974. MacDonald died in 2011.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains news articles, photographs, and internal memos about William L. MacDonald, Professor of Art History. It also contains photos taken by MacDonald and used in his book, Northampton: Architecture and Buildings (1975).
MacDonald, William L.
- Professor of Art 1965, 1965-2010 (Box 942, Folder 1)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: City Buildings, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 2)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: Ariel Views, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 3)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: Smith College, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 4)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: Ariel Views, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 5)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: City Buildings, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 6)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: City Buildings, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 7)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photograph: Smith College, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 8)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photograph: Smith College, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 9)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photograph: Ariel Views, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 10)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: City Buildings, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 11)
- Publications: Northampton, MA, Architecture and Buildings – Photographs: City Buildings, 1974 (Box 942, Folder 12)